Welcome to this course on building systems
using the chat API
previously easier and I presented
the course on how to prompt charge API,
but the system requires
much more than a single prompt
or a single call to an animal
large language model.
In this short course, we'd like to share
with you best practices
for building a complex application
using an 11.
We use the running example of building
an end to end customer service
assistant system that chains
multiple calls to a language model
using different instructions depending
on the output of the previous call,
and sometimes even looking things up
from external sources.
So, for example, giving a user input like
tell me about what TVs are for sale.
We'd use the following steps
to process this.
First, you can evaluate the input
to make sure it doesn't
contain any problematic content
such as hateful speech.
Next, the system will process the input.
It will identify
what type of query this is.
Is it complaints or product
information request and so on.
Once it has established
that it is a product inquiry,
it will retrieve the relevant information
about TVs
and use a language model
to write a helpful response.
Finally, you'll check the output
to make sure it isn't problematic,
such as inaccurate
or inappropriate answers.
One theme you see throughout this
course is an application.
Often these multiple internal steps,
they're invisible to the end user.
You often want to sequentially process
user inputs in multiple steps
to get to the final output
that is then shown to the user.
And as you've built
complex systems using labs
over the long term, you often
want to also keep on improving the system.
So also share of you
what the process of developing an ARM
based application feels like
and some best practices for evaluating
and improving the system over time.
We're grateful to many people
that had contributed
to this short course on the open air site.
We're grateful to Andrew KONDRACKE,
Joe Palermo, Boris Power and Ted Sanders,
and from the Deep Learning Team,
thank you also to Jeff
Lodwick at issue and Tommy Nelson.
Through this short course,
we hope you'll come away
confident in your abilities
to build a complex multistep application
and also be set up to maintain
and keep on improving it.
Let's dive in.