In this
section, we'll focus on tasks to process
inputs, either tasks that take the input
and generate a useful output, often
through a series of steps.
It is sometimes important for the model
to reason in detail about a problem
before answering a specific question.
And if you took our previous course chart
prompt engineering
for developers, you will have seen
a number of examples of this.
Sometimes a model
might make reasoning errors
by rushing to an incorrect conclusion.
So we can reframe the query
to request a series of relevant
reasoning steps
before the model provides a final answer
so that it can think longer
and more methodically about the problem.
And in general, we call the strategy
of asking the model to reason
about a problem and steps
chain of thought reasoning.
For some applications,
the reasoning process
that our model uses to arrive at a final
answer would be inappropriate to share
with the user.
For example, in tutoring applications,
we may want to encourage students
to work on their own answers.
But a model's reasoning process
about the student's solution
could reveal the answer to the student's
inner monologue as a tactic
that can be used to mitigate this.
And this is just a fancy way of saying hiding the model's reasoning from the user.
The idea of
in a monologue is to instruct the model
to put parts of the output
that are meant to be hidden
from the user into a structured format
that makes passing them easy.
Then, before presenting the output
to the user, the output is passed
and only part of
the output is made visible.
So remember the classification problem
from a previous video.
When we ask the model to classify
a customer query
into a primary and secondary category.
And based on that classification, we might
want to take different instructions.
Imagine the customer query had been
classified into the product information
category in the next instructions
will want to include information
about the products we have available.
And so in this case,
the classification would have been primary
general inquiry,
secondary product information.
And so let's dive into an
example starting from there.
So let's start with our usual set up.
So for this in a monologue example,
we'll start with our same
two limiters that we've been using.
And now let's
go through our system message.
And so what we're doing here
is asking the model to reason
about the answer
before coming to its conclusion.
So the instruction is follow these steps
to answer the customer queries.
The customer query will be delimited
with four hashtags or delimiter.
So now we've split this up into steps.
So the first step is to decide
whether the user
is asking a question
about a specific product or products.
And a product category doesn't count.
Step two So if the user is asking
about specific product,
identify whether the products
are in the following list.
And now we've included
a list of available products.
So here we have five available products
that all varieties of laptops
and these are all made up
products.
They were actually generated by GBG for
step three.
If the message contains
products in the list
above, list any assumptions that the user
is making in that message.
For example, that Laptop X is bigger
than a laptop Y or that Laptop
Z has a two year warranty.
For example.
Step four is
if the user made any assumptions.
Figure out whether the assumption is true
based on your product information.
And step five is first politely correct.
The customer's incorrect assumptions,
if applicable,
only mentioned or reference products
in the list of five available products,
as these are the only five products
that the store sells.
And answer the customer
in a friendly tone.
And this kind of very pedantic
instructions are probably unnecessary
for a more advanced
language model like Djibouti four.
And then
ask the model to use a following format.
So step one.
It's a limit to its reasoning,
step to the limits of reasoning and so on.
And using the delimiter will mean
that it will be easier for us later
to get just this response to the customer
and kind of cut off
everything before.
So now let's try an example.
Use a message.
So our message is
by how much is a blue wave Chromebook
more expensive than the tech pro desktop?
So let's take a look at these
two products.
The blue wave Chromebook is 249 99
and the tech pro
desktop is actually 999 99.
This is not actually true.
And so let's see how the model handles
this user request.
So we'll format into our messages array
and we'll get a response
and then we'll print it.
And so what we're hoping for
is that the model takes all of these
different steps and realizes that the user
has made an incorrect assumption
and then follows the final step
to politely correct that user.
And so within this one prompt,
we've actually maintained
a number of different complex states
that the system could be in.
So, you know, at
any given point,
that could be a different output
from the previous step
and we would want to do
something different.
For example,
if the user hadn't made any assumptions in
in step three, then in step four,
we wouldn't actually have any output.
So this is a pretty complicated
instruction for the model.
So let's see if it did it right.
So step one, the user is asking a question
about specific products,
the asking about the price difference
between these two products.
The user assumes that the blue wave
Chromebook is more expensive
than the textbook pro
and this assumption is actually incorrect
reasoning through taking longer
to think about the problem
in the same way
that human would also take some time
to reason
about an answer to any given question.
The model performs better
if it also has time to think.
And so the final response to the user is
the blue wave
Chromebook is actually less expensive
than the tech, but pro the textbook pro
desktop costs
999 99 while the blue wave Chromebook
costs 249 99.
And so let's see
another example of a user message.
And also at this point,
feel free to pause the video
and try your own messages.
So let's format this user message.
So the question is, do you sell TVs?
And if you remember in our product list,
we've only listed two different computers.
So let's see what the model says.
So in this case, step one,
the user is asking if the store sells TVs,
but TVs are not listed
in the available products.
So as you can see, the model
then skips to the response to use a step
because it realizes that the intermediary
steps are not actually necessary.
I will say that we did ask for the output
in this specific format.
So technically the model hasn't
exactly followed our request.
Again, more advanced
models will be better at doing that.
And so in this case,
our response to the user is, I'm sorry,
but we do not sell TVs at the store
and then it missed the available products.
So again, feel free
to try some of your own responses.
And so now we only really want
this part of the response.
We wouldn't want to show
the earlier parts to the user.
So what we can do is actually just
cut the string at the last occurrence
of this delimiter token
or string of four hash tags
and then only print the final
part of the model output.
So let's write
some code to get
only the final part of this string.
So we're going to use a try accept block
to gracefully handle errors
in case the model has some kind of
unpredictable output and doesn't
actually use these these characters.
And so we're going to say
our final response is the response,
and then we're going to split the string
at the delimiter string.
And because we want the final comments,
we just want to get the last
item in the output list,
and then we're going to strip
any whitespace
because as you can see, there
might be whitespace after the characters
and we're going to catch any errors
and have a fallback response,
which is sorry, I'm having
I'm having trouble right now.
Please
try asking another question
and then let's print
our final response.
And so as you can see, we just cut
the string to get this final output.
And so this is what we would show
to the user
if we were building this
into an application.
And overall, I just want to call out
this prompt might be slightly convoluted
for this task.
You might not actually need
all of these intermediate steps.
And so why don't you try and see
if you can find an easier way to do
the same task in your in prompt
and in general,
finding the optimal trade off
in prompt complexity requires
some experimentation.
So definitely good
to try a number of different prompts
before deciding to use one.
And in the next video
we'll learn another strategy to handle
complex tasks by splitting these complex
tasks into a series of simpler subtotal
rather than trying to do
the whole task in one prompt.