In this video, we'll learn how to split
complex
tasks into a series of simpler subtasks
by chaining multiple prompts together.
You might be wondering why would you split
up a task into multiple prompts
when you could achieve it with one prompt
and chain of thought reasoning
like we learned in the previous video?
We've already shown that language
models are very good at following complex
instructions, especially the more advanced
models like GPT four.
So let me explain why we would do this
with two analogies
comparing chain of thought,
reasoning and chaining multiple prompts.
The first analogy to compare
the two is the difference between
cooking a complex meal in one go versus
cooking it in stages.
Using one long, complicated instruction
can be like trying
to cook a complex meal all at once
while you have to manage
multiple ingredients, cooking techniques
and timings simultaneously.
It can be challenging
to keep track of everything and ensure
that each component is cooked perfectly.
Training prompts, on the other hand,
is like cooking the meal in stages
where you focus on one component
at a time, ensuring
that each part is cooked
correctly before moving on to the next.
This approach breaks down
the complexity of the task,
making it easier to manage
and reducing the likelihood of errors.
However,
this approach might be unnecessary
and overcomplicated
for a very simple recipe.
A slightly better analogy for the same
thing is the difference between reading
spaghetti code with everything in one long
file and a simple modular program.
The thing that can make spaghetti code bad
and difficult to debug
is ambiguity and complex dependencies
between different parts of the logic.
The same can be true of a complex single
step task submitted to a language model.
Chaining problems is a powerful strategy.
When you have a workflow
where you can maintain
the state of the system at any given point
and take different actions
depending on the current state.
And so an example of the current state
would be after you've classified
an incoming customer query,
the state would be the classification.
So the it's an account question
or it's a product question.
And then based on the state,
you might do something different.
Each subtasks
contains only the instructions required
for a single state of the task,
which makes the system easier to manage.
Make sure the model has
all the information
it needs to carry out a task and reduces
the likelihood of errors.
As I mentioned, this approach
can also reduce and lower costs
since longer problems
with more tokens cost more to run.
And outlining all steps
might be unnecessary in some cases.
Another benefit of this approach
is that it is also easier to test
which steps might be failing more often,
or to have a human in the loop
at a specific step.
So to summarize,
because this is a long explanation.
Instead of describing a whole complex
workflow and dozens of bullet points
or several paragraphs in one prompt,
like in the previous video,
it might be better
to keep track of the state externally
and then inject relevant
instructions as needed.
And what makes a problem complex?
I think in general a problem is complex.
If there are many different instructions
and potentially all of them could apply
to any given situation, as these
are the cases where it could become hard
for the model to reason about what to do.
And as you build with and interact
with these models more,
you'll gain an intuition for when
to use this strategy versus the previous.
And one additional benefit
that I didn't mention yet
is that it also allows the model
to use external tools
at certain points of the workflow
if necessary.
For example,
it might decide to look something up
in a product catalog
or call an API or search a knowledge base,
something that could not be achieved
with a single prompt.
So with that, let's dive into an example.
So we're going to use the same example
as in the previous video
when we want to answer a customer's
question about a specific product.
But this time we'll use more products
and also break the steps
down into a number of different prompts.
So we'll use the same delimiter
that we've been using
in the previous videos,
and that's read through our system
message.
You will be provided with customer service
queries.
The customer service query will be
delimited with four hashtag characters.
I'll put a python list of objects
where each object has the following format
category,
which is one of these predefined fields
or products and this is a list of products
that must be found in the allowed products
below.
While the categories and products must be
found in the customer service query.
If a product
does mentioned, it must be associated
with the correct category
in the allowed products list below.
If no products or categories
are found, output an empty list.
So now we have allowed list of products.
So we have the categories and
then the products within those categories.
Now, final instruction is only output.
The list of objects with nothing else.
So next we have our user message.
And so this messages.
Tell me about the small x profile on
the photo is not camera the DSL one.
Also tell me about your TV's.
So we're asking
about two specific products
and also the general category
of televisions
on both of these products are mentioned
in the allowed products list.
Then we have a television section as well,
and we format the system message
and user message into the messages array,
and then we get the completion
from the model.
So as you can see for our output,
we have a list of objects
and each object has category and products.
So we have the small X pro phone
and the photo snapped DSLR camera.
And then in the final object
we actually only have a category
because we didn't
mention any specific TVs.
And so
the benefit of outputting
this structured response is that we can
then read it into a list in Python,
which is very nice.
And so let's try another example.
So our second user message is
my router isn't working.
And if you notice in the list,
we don't actually have any routers
and then
format this correctly
and get the completion.
And so as you can see in this case,
the output is an empty list.
And so now that we have this step
to identify the category and products,
if we find any products and categories,
we want to note some information
about those requested products
and categories into the prompt
so that we can better
answer the customer question.
And so in our workflow,
the state now after this prompt is run
as either products have been listed
or they haven't been listed.
And in that case
we wouldn't try to look anything up
because there's nothing to look up.
Well, so if I were to actually build this
into a system,
I might use category
names, maybe something like
computers and laptops or something
to avoid any weirdness
with spaces and special characters.
But this should work for now.
So now we want to look up some information
about the products
that the user mentioned.
So about this phone, this camera,
and about the TV's in general.
And so we need to have
some kind of product catalog
to look up this information from.
So here we have our product information.
I just paste it in.
So as you can see,
we have a large number of products
available at our store
and all of these products are fake
and were actually generated by GBG for.
And so for each product
we have a couple of different fields.
We have name category, brand
warranty and so on.
And so the products is just a dictionary
from product name
to this object that contains
the information about the product.
And notice
that each product has a category.
So remember,
we want to look up information
about the products
that the user asks about.
So we need to define some helper functions
to allow us to look up
product information by product name.
So let's create a function
gap, product by name,
the input the name,
and then we're going to return
product dictionary
and we're going to get the value
for the item with the name as the key.
And then I'll pull
back is just going to be none.
And so we also want to define
another helper function
to get all of the products
for a certain category.
For example,
when the user is asking about the TVs
we have,
we want to load all of the information
about all of the different TVs.
So get products
by category,
the input, the category name string.
And to do this, we want to look through
all of the products
in the product's dictionary and check
each one to see if the category
is equal to the input category.
And if so, we want to return that.
So we'll do this as follows.
So first we want to loop through
each product and we have to get the values
because we need to actually
access the category, which is the value.
And then we'll return this product.
If the product
category
is equal to
our input category.
So let's
do an example
for each of these helper functions.
So first
we have a product called the Tech pro
Ultrabook,
so let's get the product information
by name.
So here you can see we've just fetched all
of the product information
and let's do an example to
get all of the products for our category.
So let's get all of the products
in the computers and laptops category.
Hey, you see,
we fetched one of the products
with this category.
So let's continue our example.
And just to remember where we are,
that's the user message.
So the user message was
tell me about the smart X pro
phone on the camera, on the TVs.
And then the initial output from the model
from the first step was this.
And so what we also need to do
is read this output from the model,
which is a string.
We need to pass that into a list
so that we can use it as input
to the help of functions
that we just wrote.
So that's why
a helper function to do this.
So we're going to use the Python
JSON module and we're going to write
a function
called read string to list and very
descriptive title.
The input string.
And so first we'll just check
if the input string
is non
in case something in the previous step
failed.
We're just going to return nothing
and now
we're going to have a try except block
to make sure that we catch any errors.
And so first
we replace any single quotes
with double quotes in the input string
to make sure we can pass the Jason
and then we're going to use the JSON nodes
function to read the input string
into the array or the left.
And then we're going to return this.
And if there's a decode error, we're going
to print the error and then return non.
So let's try this with our example.
So we're going to get our category
and product list using the read string
to list helper function and apply it
to this response from the model.
And then we're going to print this list
so it should look the same.
Let me run this first.
And so as you can see, it's
just the same thing, except now
the type of this variable
is actually a list instead of a string.
So the whole point of what we're doing
is to get the product information into
a less that we can add
to the next instruction to the model,
which is going to be the instruction where
we ask it to answer the user question.
And so to do this,
we need to put the product information
into a nice string format
that we can add to the prompt.
And so let's also create a helper function
to do this.
So we're going to call it
generate output string,
and it's going to take in the list of data
that we just created.
So this
and then I'm going to copy
some code and then we'll walk through
what it's doing.
So now I'm going to patient some code
and show you an example
and then we'll talk about
what this function is doing.
So we're going to get the product
information from our first user message.
And so we're going to use this helper
function, generate output string
on our category and product list,
which if we remember was this.
And so here we have one of the product
information for the products
that were in the mentioned
in the user message.
So we have the phone that they mentioned,
we have the camera that they mentioned,
and then we have all of the product
information for all of our TVs.
And this is information
that will be helpful for the model
to be able
to answer the user's initial question.
And if you're interested in
how this function works,
I'll give a brief overview,
but you can feel free to pause the video
and read it more thoroughly.
So it basically just loops through
all of the objects
in this list
and first checks with that products.
If so, it gets the
information for each product
and then it checks off as a category.
If they want any products.
So that would be for this object,
for example.
And then it gets all of the product
information for the products
in that category,
and it just adds them to this string
and then that's what it returns.
So at this point,
we've found the relevant product
information to answer the user question.
Now it's time for the model
to actually answer the question.
So let's have our system message.
So this is the instruction here.
Our customers service
assistant for a large electronics store
respond in a friendly and helpful tone
with, let's say,
with very concise answers.
Make sure to ask the user relevant
follow up questions.
So I want this to be
an interactive experience for the user.
And so just as a reminder,
this was our initial user message.
I'll just add it again.
And so now we're going
to have our messages array,
and this is the input to the model.
So let's go through this.
We have our first message,
which is the system message.
As usual,
we have the user message
and then we have this
additional assistant message,
and this is the message
that contains all of the product
information that we just looked up.
And so we're saying relevant product
information, new line,
and then this product information
that we just found.
And so now the model has the relevant
context.
It needs to be able
to answer this user's question.
So let's get the final response
and print it.
And we're hoping that in the models
going to use relevant information from
the product information
in order to answer the user
in a helpful way.
So first it tells the user about the smart
phone,
tells the user about the photo
stop camera and then talks
about the different televisions
that we have in stock
and then ask the follow up question.
So as you can
see by breaking this up
into a series of steps,
we were able to load information
relevant to the user query
to give the model the relevant context
it needed to answer the question
effectively.
So you might be wondering
why are we selectively loading product
descriptions into the prompt
instead of including all of them
and letting the model use the information
it needs?
And so what I mean by this is why didn't
we just include all of this product
information in the prompt and we wouldn't
have to bother with all of this
intermediate steps to actually look up
the product information.
There's a couple of reasons for this.
Firstly,
including all of the product descriptions,
might make the context
more confusing for the model,
just as it would
for a person trying to process
a large amount of information at once.
I will say this is a lot less relevant
for more advanced models like JPG for
especially when the context was
well structured
like it is in this example on
the model is small enough
just to ignore the information
that clearly isn't relevant.
The next reasons are more compelling.
So the second reason is that language
models have context limitations.
A fixed number of tokens
allowed as input and output.
So if you have a large number of products,
imagine you had a huge product catalog.
You wouldn't even be able to fit all of
the descriptions into the contacts window.
And the final reason is that
including one of the product descriptions
could be expensive as you pay by token
when using language models.
So by selectively loading information,
you can reduce the cost
of generating responses.
In general, the time ending
when dynamically load information
into the models context
and allowing the model to decide
when it needs more information
is one of the best ways
to augment the capabilities
of these models.
And to reiterate,
you should think of a language model
as a reasoning agent that requires
the necessary context to draw useful
conclusions and perform useful tasks.
And so in this case,
we had to give the model
the product information
and then it was able to reason about that
product information
to create a useful answer for the user.
And in this example,
we only of a call to a specific function
or functions
to get the product description by product
name, want to get the category products
by category name,
but the models are actually good
at deciding when to use a variety
of different tools and can use them
properly with instructions.
And this is the idea behind
chatting about plug ins.
We tell the model what tools
it has access to and what they do,
and it chooses to use them
when it needs information
from a specific source or wants to take
some other appropriate action.
In our example,
we can only look up information
by exact product and category name match,
but there are also more advanced
techniques for information retrieval.
One of the most effective ways to retrieve
information is using text embeddings
and embeddings can be used to implement
efficient knowledge retrieval
over a large corpus to find information
related to a given query.
One of the key advantages of using text
embeddings is that they
enable fuzzy or semantic search,
which allows you
to find relevant information
without using the exact keywords.
So in our example, we wouldn't necessarily
need the exact name of the product,
but we could do a more a search with a
more general query, like a mobile phone
for planning to create a
comprehensive course on how to use
embeddings for various applications soon.
So stay tuned.
And with that,
let's move on to the next video
where we're going to talk about
how to evaluate the outputs from
the language model.