And the
last video you saw how to evaluate.
And I'll put in an example
where it had the right answer
and so could write down a function
to explicitly
just tell us
if the outputs the right categories.
And this are products.
But one of the elements used to generate
text in there is in just one
right piece of text.
Let's take a look at an approach
for how to evaluate that type of outputs.
Here's my usual helper functions
and and given the customer message,
tell me about this one x pro phone
and it it's that camera and so on.
Here are a few utils to get me
the assistance.
Answer.
This is basically the process that user
has stepped through in earlier videos.
And so here's the assistant answer.
Sure, we have the whole smartphone,
the slice pro phone and so on
and so forth.
So how can you evaluate
if this is a good answer or not?
Seems like there are lots of possible
good answers.
One way to evaluate
this is to write a rubric,
meaning a set of guidelines to evaluate
this answer on different dimensions,
and then use that to decide whether or not
you're satisfied with this answer.
Let me show you how to do that.
So let me create a little data structure
to store the customization
as well as the product info.
So here I'm going to specify a prompt
for evaluating the assistant answer using
what's called the rubric.
I'll explain the second what that means.
But this is in the system message
and the system
evaluates how well the customer service
agent answers the user question.
But it's in the context
that the customer service
agents are using the general response.
So this response is what we had further up
the notebook.
What that was the assistant answer
and we're going to specify the data.
And this problem was the customer
message was the context.
That is was the product and category
information that was provided.
And then what was the output of the lab.
And then this is a rubric.
So we want to compare the factual content
to something as of the content,
you know, differences.
So grammar, punctuation
and then we wanted to check a few things
like is the assistant response
based only on the content provided?
Does the answer include information
that is not provided in the context?
Is there any disagreement between response
and the context?
So this is called a rubric
and this specifies what we think
the answer should get right
for us to consider as a good answer.
Then finally, we wanted to print out
yes or no
and so on.
And now, if we were to
run this evaluation, this is what you get.
So says the assistant response
is based on the content provided
it does not in this case
seem to make up new information.
There isn't disagreements.
Use Ask two questions.
Answer question one.
Then ask the question
to answer both questions.
So we would look for this output
and maybe conclude
that this is a pretty good response.
And one notes sure, I'm using
the charge of these 3.5 turbo model
for this evaluation.
For a more robust evaluation,
it might be worth considering using GPP
for because even if you deploy 3.5
turbo in production and generate
a lot of text, if your evaluation
is a more sporadic exercise,
then it may be
prudent to pay for the somewhat
more expensive GP for API call
to get a more rigorous evaluation
of the upwards of one design patterns.
I hope your take away from this
is that you can specify a rubric,
meaning a
list of
criteria by which to evaluate an output.
Then you can actually use another API call
to evaluate your first output.
That's one of the design patterns
that could be useful
for some applications,
which is if you can specify
an ideal response.
So here I'm going to specify a test
example where the customer messages
tell me about the spikes
profile and so on.
And she has an ideal answer.
So this is if you have an expert human
customer service representative,
write a really good answer.
And the expert says
this would be a great answer.
Of course, the spice profile of it
and so on, it goes on
to give a lot of helpful information.
Now it is unreasonable to expect any lab
to generate this exact answer.
We're four words, and in classical
natural language processing techniques,
there are some traditional metrics
for measuring
If the output is similar to this expert
human rated outputs.
For example, there's
something called the Blue Score EU.
Then you can search online
to read more about.
They can measure how similar
one piece of Texas from another,
but it turns out there's an
even better way,
which is you can use a prompt
which you specify here
to Austin 11 to compare
how well the automatically generated
customer service agent outputs corresponds
to the ideal expert response
that was written by a human.
They just showed up above
just the prompts
we can use,
which is we're going to use an arm
and tell it to be an assistant
that evaluates how well the customer
service agent has is just a question.
By comparing the response
that was the automatic generated one
to the ideal expert
human written response.
And so going to give it the data,
which is what the customer requests.
Once the expert written it responds
and then what it actually outputs
and just rubric comes from the open,
the eye open source framework,
which is a fantastic framework
with many evaluation methods, contributed
both by open the developers
and by the broader open source community.
In fact, if you once you could contribute
an equal to that framework yourself
to help others evaluate their
launch language, both outputs.
So in this rubric, we told the ELM to
compare the factual content to the same.
So the expert answer and all differences
allow grammar, punctuation and
the pause
the video and read through this in detail.
But the key is
we ask it to carry the comparison
and outputs a score from A to Z, depending
on whether the submitted answer
is a subset of expensive
and is fully consistent versus
the sum of the answer
is a superset of the answer.
But this would be consistent with it.
This might mean that hallucinated
or made up some additional facts.
Sympathizer contains
all the details as an expert answer,
whether it is disagreements
or whether it be as is differ.
But these differences still matter
from the perspective of actuality,
and the lab will pick
whichever of these seems to be
the most appropriate description.
So here's the assistant answer
that we had just now.
I think it's a pretty good answer.
But now let's see what the things
when I compress the assistant
as to test that idea
looks like it got an eight.
And so things the submitted answer
is a subset of the expert answer
and is fully consistent with it.
And that sounds right to me.
This assistant
as is much shorter than the long expert
answer up top,
but it does hopefully is consistent.
Once again,
I'm using 3.5 turbo in this example,
but to get a more rigorous
evaluation, just
it might make sense to use
D four in your old application.
Now let's try something totally different.
I'm going to have a very different
assistant answer.
Life is like a box of chocolate call
from a movie called Forrest Gump.
And if we were to evaluate that,
it outputs D
and it concludes that there's
a disagreement with his submitted answer.
Life is like a box of chocolate
and the expert answer.
So the correctly assesses
this to be a pretty terrible answer.
And so that's it.
I hope you take away from this video
to design patterns
versus even without an expert
provided ideal answer.
If you can write a rubric,
you can use one element
to evaluate
another of outputs and seconds.
If you can provide an expert provided,
if you answer,
then that can help you better compare.
If and if a specific assistant output
is similar to the expert provided idea
answer I hope that helps you to evaluate
your own system's outputs.
So that's both during development
as well as when the system is running
and you're getting responses.
You can continue to monitor
this performance and also have these tools
to continuously evaluate and keep on
improving the performance of your system.