In this video, we'll put together
everything we've learned in the
previous videos to create an end to end
example of a customer service assistant.
We'll go through the following steps.
First, we'll track the input
to see if it flagged from an API.
Second, if it does,
it will extract the list of products
that if the products are found,
we'll try to look them up for.
We'll answer the user question
with the model.
And finally, we'll put the answer
through the moderation API.
And if it is not flagged,
we'll return it to the user.
So we have all set up.
We have this additional imports,
this is a Python package
we use for a chat bot UI.
And so I'm going to paste
in a function process user message
and I'm actually going to run
an example for us
and then we'll talk through the function.
So we
have our user input that we've been using.
Tell me about the smart expression
on the camera.
Also, tell me about TV.
So let's run this
first.
Let's run this.
So as you can see,
we're going through the steps
to answer the user question.
So the first stop, the motivation stop.
The second step is extracting
the list of products.
The third step is looking
at the product information.
And so now with this product information,
the model is off
is trying to answer the question.
As we've seen in the previous videos.
And then finally, it puts the response
through the Moderation
API again to make sure it's safe
to show to the user.
And so this is the response
that we're now familiar with.
And so
let's talk through a little bit
of what's happening.
So we have our helper function process
using message
annotation.
The user input,
which is the current message
and an array
of all of the messages so far.
And this is when we build the chat UI.
So the first step checking to see
if the input flags moderation API.
We covered this in a previous video.
If the input is flagged, then
we tell the user
that we can't process the request.
If it is not flagged,
we try to extract the list of products
as we did in the previous video.
Then we try to look up the product.
And in this case, if no products are
found, this will just be an empty string.
Then we answer the user question.
So we give the conversation history
and the new messages
with the relevant product information.
So we get the response
and then we run this response
through the Moderation API.
If it's flagged,
we tell the user that we can't
provide this information.
Maybe we'll say something.
Let me connect you
and you could take some subsequent step.
So let's put this all together with a nice
UI and try to have a conversation.
So here we have a function
that will just accumulate the messages
as we interact with the assistant.
And feel free to analyze the video, to
understand in more detail how this works.
And of course, feel free to do the same
for the really long process.
Use a message function
that we just saw as well.
So now we're going to pay set our code
to display the chat UI.
So if we run this now,
let's try and have a conversation
with the customer service assistant.
So let's ask what TV is.
Do you have?
And under the hood, the system is going
through all of the steps in the process.
Use message function.
So it's listed a variety of different TVs.
So now let's ask which is the cheapest,
I guess
that's going through all the same steps.
But this time it's passing
the conversation history as well into
the prompts.
Okay.
So it's telling us that the speaker is
the cheapest TV related product we have.
Interesting.
Let's see what the most expensive is.
So the most expensive TV is the center
view.
Eight K TV.
So let's ask for more information
about it.
Tell me more about it.
And so we've
received some more information about
this television.
So in this example,
we've combined the techniques
we've learned throughout the course
to create a comprehensive system
with a chain of steps that evaluates user
inputs, processes them,
and then tracks the output
by monitoring the quality of the system
across a larger number of inputs.
You can alter the steps and improve
the overall performance of your system.
Maybe we might find
that our approach could be better
because some of the steps, maybe
some of the steps aren't even necessary.
Maybe we'll find a better retrieval method
and so on.
We'll discuss this more in the next video.