In the previous few videos,
users shown how to build an application
using an hour from evaluating these inputs
to processing the inputs to then doing
final open checking
and before you show the outputs to a user.
Obviously built such a system.
How do you know how is working?
And maybe even as you deploy it
and let users use it,
how can you track how is doing
and finding these shortcomings
and continue to improve the quality
of the answers in the system?
In this video, I'd like to share with you
some best practices
for evaluating the outputs of an Elm.
And I want to show you
specifically what it feels like
to build one of these systems.
One key distinction between what
you hear me talk about in this video
and what you may have seen in more
traditional machine learning supervised
only applications is because you can build
such an application so quickly.
The methods evaluating it,
it tends not to start off with a test set.
Instead, you often end up gradually
building up a set of test examples.
Let me show you what I mean by that.
You may remember this diagram
from the second video about how problems
development speeds up
the core parts of multiple development
from maybe months
to just minutes or hours.
Like most, a very small number of days
in the
traditional supervised learning approach.
If you needed to collect, say, 10,000
people examples anyway,
then the incremental costs of collecting
another 1000 test examples isn't that bad.
So in the traditional supervised
learning setting,
it was not unusual to click
a training site, collect
a development set or hold our
cross-validation set in a test set,
and then tap those at hand
throughout this development process.
But if you're able to specify
a prompt in just minutes
and get something working in hours,
then it would seem like a huge pain
if you had to pause for a long time
to collect a thousand test examples
because you can now get this working
with zero training examples.
So when building an application
using an element,
this is what it often feels like.
First you would tune the prompts on
just a small handful of examples.
Maybe one, two, 3 to 5 examples
and try to get a prompt
that works on them.
And then as you have the system
undergo additional testing,
you occasionally run into a few examples
that are tricky.
The prompt doesn't work on them
or the outcome doesn't work on them.
And in that case, you can take these
additional one or two or three
or five examples
and add them to the set to your testing on
to just add additional tricky examples
opportunistically.
Eventually,
you have enough of these examples
you've added to your slowly
growing development set that it becomes
a bit inconvenient to manually run
every example through the prompt.
Every time you change the problem
and then you start to develop metrics
to measure performance
on just a small set of examples
such as maybe average accuracy
and one
interesting aspect of this process
is if you decide at any moment in time
your system is working well enough,
you can stop right there
and not go on to the next bullet.
And the fact that many deploy applications
that start at maybe the first or
the second bullet and are running actually
and they're running just fine.
Now, if your hand-built
development set the evaluating
the model long isn't giving you sufficient
confidence yet in the performance
of your system, then that's when you may
go to the next step of of collecting
a randomly sample set of examples.
To tune the model to and this would
continue to be a development set
through a whole lot of cross-validation.
So that could be quite
because to be quite common
to continue to tune your prompt to this
and only if you need even higher fidelity
estimate of the performance of the system,
then might you collect and
use the holdout test sets
that you don't even look at yourself
when you're tuning the model.
And so
step four tends to be more important
if, say,
your system is getting the right answer
91% of the time.
He wants it to that to get it
to give the right answer.
92 or 93% of the time.
Then you do need
the largest end of examples to measure
those differences
between 91 and 93% performance.
And then only if you really need
an unbiased,
fair estimate of
how was the system doing, then
you need to go beyond the development
set to also collect a holdout test set.
One important caveat
I've seen a lot of applications of large
language models
where there isn't meaningful risk of harm
if it gives not quite the right answer,
but obviously for any high stakes
applications,
if there's a risk of bias
or inappropriate outputs
causing harm to someone,
then the responsibility
to collect a test set to rigorously
evaluate the performance of the system
to make sure it's doing the right thing
before you use it.
That becomes much more important.
But if, for example,
if you are using it to summarize articles
just for yourself to read and no one else,
then maybe the risk of harm
is more modest
and you can stop early in this process
without going to the expense of bullets
four and five and collecting larger
datasets
on which to evaluate your algorithm.
So in this example,
let me start with the usual
helper functions.
First,
use a utils
function
to get a list of products and categories.
So in the computers in that top category,
there's a list of computers, laptops
and smartphones and CSC category.
So this is smartphones and systems
and so on.
For other categories.
Now, let's say
this hospital, the actress is given
a user input such as what TV can they buy?
If I'm on the budget
to retrieve the relevant
categories in products so that we have
the right info to answer the user's query.
So here's a prompt for you
to pause the video
and read through this in detail
if you wish.
But the prompt specifies
a set of instructions
and actually gives the language model
one example of a good output.
This is sometimes called a few short
lets actually one side prompting because
we're actually using a user message
in the system.
Message
to give it one example of good output.
This one says
I want the most expensive computer.
You know,
let's just return all the computers
because we don't have pricing information.
Now let's use this front on the hospital
message.
Which TV can I buy if I'm on a budget?
And so we're passing in
to this both the prompt customer,
such as zero as was the Partizan category.
This is a information that we retrieve
a top using the UTILS function.
And here in this cell,
the relevant information to this query,
which is under the category
televisions and home theater systems,
this is on this of TVs and home
theater systems.
That's relevant
to see how well the prompt is doing.
You may be validated on a second prompt.
Of course, that says I mean the challenge
if I'm a smart phone,
it looks like us correctly retrieving
this data.
How do we smartphones, accessories
and this rather than products?
And here's another one.
So what computers do you have?
And hopefully I retrieve
a list of the computers.
So here I have three prompts
and if you are developing this prompt
for the first time,
it would be quite reasonable to to have
one or two or three examples like this.
And to keep on tuning the prompt
until it gives appropriate outputs,
until the prompt is retrieving
the relevant products and categories
to the customer requests
for all of your prompts.
All three of them in this example.
And if the prompt had been missing
some products or something,
then what we would do
is probably go back to edit
the prompt a few times
until it gets it right.
On all three of these prompts.
After
you've gotten the system to this point,
you might then start running the system
in testing,
maybe send it to internal test users
or try using it yourself
and just run it for a while
to see what happens.
And sometimes you will run across a prompt
that it fails on.
So here's an example of a prompt
Tell people to slice pro phone and fill
this out camera Also what TVs you have.
So when I run it on this prompt
it looks like is outputting
the right data,
but it also outputs a bunch of text here.
This extra chunk makes it harder
to parse this into a python.
This dictionaries so we don't like that
is outputting this extra chunk.
So when you run across one example
that the system fails on,
then common practice is to just no doubt
that this is a somewhat tricky example.
So let's add this to our set of examples
that we're going to test the system
on systematically.
And if you keep on running the system
for a while longer, maybe it works.
On those examples.
We tested the prompt to see examples of
maybe we'll work on many examples, but
just by chance you might run across
another example where January's an error.
So this custom message
four also causes the system to output
a bunch of junk text
at the end that we don't
want.
Try to be helpful
to get all this extra text.
We actually don't want this
as So at this point,
you may have run this prompt
maybe on hundreds of examples.
Maybe your test uses,
but you would just take the examples.
The tricky ones is doing poorly on
and now have this
set of five examples
in text from 0 to 4 have.
This are the five examples that you use
to further fine tune the prompts.
And in both of these examples
I'll put a bunch of extra junk
text at the end that we don't want.
And after a little bit of trial and error,
you might decide to modify
the prompts as follows.
So here's a new prompt.
This is called from V two.
But what we did here was
we added to the prompt.
Did not output any additional
text is not in Jason format just emphasize
piece of output this Jason stuff
and add in a second example using the user
and assistant message for future property
where the user also cheapest computer
and in both of the few shot examples,
we're demonstrating to the system
a response
where it gives only Jason outputs.
So here's the extra thing that we just
added to the problem to the output.
Any additional text
is not in Jason formats and we use future
use the one future system
one and Fichajes to future assistant to
to give it two of these few shot
prompts
suddenly shift into to find that prompt
and you have to go back and manually rerun
this prompt on all five of the examples
of user inputs, including this one
that previously had given a broken output.
You find that it now
gives a correct output.
And if you were to go back and rerun
this new problem,
this is from version
V two on that customer message example
that results in the broken output
with extra junk after the JSON output,
then this will generate a better output
and I'm not going to do it here,
but I encourage you to pause the video
and rerun it yourself on Custom Message
four as well on this prompt V
to see if it also generates
the correct output and hopefully it will.
I think it should.
And of course when you modify
the prompts, it's also useful to do
a bit of regression
testing to make sure that
when fixing the incorrect outputs
on prompts three and four,
it doesn't break
the outputs on from zero either.
Now you can kind of tell that
if I had to copy paste
five prompts customer such as zero
one, two, three and four into my
for the notebook and run them
and then manually look at them
to see if the output in the right
categories and products.
So you can kind of do it.
I can look at this and go, Yep,
carry TV and holidays is those products.
Yep, they'll see all of them.
But there's actually a little bit painful
to do this manually,
to manually inspect
or to look at this output
to make sure with your eyes
that this is exactly the right output.
So when the development sets,
the tuning to becomes more
than just a small handful of examples, it
then becomes useful
to start to automate the testing process.
So here is a set of ten examples
where I'm specifying
ten customer messages.
So here's the customer message
What TV for the biopharma budget
as well as what's the ideal.
So think of this
as the right answer in the test set
or really I should say development set
because we're actually tuning to this.
And so we've collected here ten examples
in text from zero through nine
where the last one is.
If the user says,
I would like to time as machine,
we have no relevant products to that.
Really Sorry.
So the idea answer is the empty set.
And now if you want to evaluate
automatically what the prompt is doing on
any of these ten examples,
here is a function to do.
So this kind of a lung function
for the pauses video and read through it
if you wish, but let me just demonstrate
what it is actually doing.
So let me print out the custom message
for custom messages zero.
Right.
So of course, customer messages.
Which TV can I buy if I'm on a budget?
And this also prints out the idea?
Answer So the idea answer is all the TVs
that we want to prompt to retrieve
and let me now call the prompt.
This is probably to
on this customer message
with that usual practice and calorie
information that's printed out.
And then we'll call to give our
we'll call
to give our responsive ideal option
to see how well
the response matches the ideal answer.
And in this case,
it did outputs the category that we wanted
and it did outputs
the entire list of products.
And so this gives it a score of 1.0.
Just to show you one more example,
it turns out that I know it gets it
wrong on the examples seven
So I change this from 0
to 7 and run it.
This is what it gets.
And then we update this to
seven as well.
So on to this customer message.
This is the idea as sir, we should all put
on the gaming consoles ancestry.
So this is gaming consoles and Cicero's,
but where's the response
here has the outputs.
It actually should have had
one, two, three, four, five
outputs.
And so it's missing some of the products.
So what I would do if I tuning the prompt
now is I would then
use a follow up to loop over
all ten of the development set examples
where we repeatedly put out the custom
message, get the idea.
And so the right answer,
call the arm to get a response evaluated
and then the accumulator and average
and then just run this
play, right?
So this would take a while to run,
but when it's done running,
this is the results we're running through.
The ten examples
it looks like example seven was wrong.
And so the fashion
recall of ten was 90% correct.
And so if you were to tune the prompts,
you can rerun this to see
if the percent correct goes up or down.
What you just saw in
this notebook is going
through the steps one,
two and three of this bullet in this.
And this already gives a pretty good
development sets of ten examples
with which to tune and validate
the prompts is working.
If you needed an additional level trigger,
then you now have the software
needed to collect a random
sample sets of maybe 100 examples
with their ideal outputs and maybe
even go beyond that to the rigor of hold
our test set the you know, even
look at why you two need to prompt
but for a lot of applications
stopping at bullet three.
But there are also certainly applications
where you could do what you just saw me
do in this with the notebook
and it gets a pretty performance system
quite quickly
with again, the important caveat that
if you're working on a safety
critical application
or an application with this
where there's non-trivial risk of harm,
then of course
it would be the responsible thing
to do to actually get a much larger test
set to really verify the performance
before you use it anywhere.
And so that's it's
I find that the workflow
of building applications using probes
is very different than the workflow
of building applications
using supervised learning.
And the pace of iteration
feels much faster.
And if you have not yet done it before,
you might be surprised at how well
and evaluate a method built
on just a few Hand-Curated tricky examples
you think with ten examples
and this is not statistically valid
for almost anything, but you might be
surprised we actually use this procedure.
How effective?
Adding a handful, just a handful
of tricky examples into development sets
might be in terms of helping
you and your team get to an effective.
So the prompt and effective system
in this video,
the outputs could be evaluated
quantitatively as in
those desired outputs, and you could tell
if it gave the desired output or not.
So the next video, let's take a look
how you can evaluate outputs
in that setting where what is the right
answer is a bit more ambiguous.