Congratulations and thank you for getting
to the end of this short course
as we conclude the course.
Let's recap the main topics we covered.
We went over details of how land works,
including subtleties
like The Tokenize
and why it can't reverse Lollipop.
We learned methods for evaluating user
inputs
to ensure the quality
and safety of the system processing inputs
using both chain of thought, reasoning
and splitting tasks into subtasks
with chain prompts and checking outputs
before showing them to users.
We also took a look at methods
for evaluating the system over time
so as to monitor
and improve its performance.
Throughout the course, we also discussed
the importance of building responsibly
with these tools,
ensuring that the model is safe
and provides appropriate responses
that are accurate, relevant
and in the turn you want.
As always, practices key
to mastering these concepts.
So we hope you'll apply
what you've learned in your own projects.
And so that's it.
There are so many exciting applications
that are yet to be built.
The world needs more people
like you building useful applications,
and we look forward to hearing
about the amazing things you build.