In this section, we'll focus on
tasks to evaluate inputs,
which can be important for ensuring
the quality and safety of the system.
Photos in which lots of independent
sets of instructions
are needed to handle different cases.
It can be beneficial to first classify
the type of query
and then use that classification
to determine which instructions to use.
This can be achieved
by defining fixed categories and hard
coding instructions that are relevant
for handling tasks in a given category.
For instance, when building a customer
service assistant,
it might be important to first classify
the type of query
and then determine which instructions
to use based on that classification.
So for example, you might give different
secondary instructions if a user asks
to close their account versus
if a user asks about a specific product.
So in the first case, you maybe add
additional instructions
about how to close the account.
And then in the second case, you might add
additional product information.
But let's see an example,
and I think it will make it more clear.
So here we have our system message,
which is the instruction
for the overall system, and we're using
this the limiter and its limiter
is just a way to separate different parts
of an instruction or output,
and it helps the model
kind of determine the different sections.
And so for this example,
we'll use the delimiter for hash tags.
And this is a nice delimiter because it's
actually represented as one token
and so has also a message.
What we're asking the model.
So you will be provided
with customer service queries.
The customer service query will be
delimited with these hash tag characters.
Classify each query into a primary
category and the secondary category,
and then provide the output in a JSON
format with the keys
primary and secondary.
And so we have our primary categories
listed here.
So billing, technical support,
account management or general inquiry.
And then below
we have the list of secondary categories.
Unsubscribe, upgrade, etc..
And so now let's
do an example of a user message.
So for our first user message, we'll use
the following.
So the user messages,
I want you to delete my profile
and all of my user data
and then we'll just format this
into a messages list
with a system message and the user message
delimited with its hash tags
and let's just take a
look and see what we think this might be.
So I want you to delete my profile.
This kind of looks like account
management,
maybe close accounts,
and let's see what the model
thinks.
Great.
So the classification from the model
is account
management as the primary category
and then close account as a secondary.
And the nice thing about asking
for a structured output like a JSON
is that you can then read this easily
into some kind of object.
So in dictionary, for example, in Python
or something else,
if using a different language
and then you can use this as the input
to a subsequent step,
I'll show you another example.
But also feel free to pause the video now
and just try your own user questions
and see how the model categorizes them.
So here's another user message.
Tell me more about your flat screen TVs.
And we just have the same messages.
Last response from the model,
and then we'll just print it.
And here we have our second
categorization, which seems correct.
And so
in general, based on the categorization
of the customer inquiry,
we can now provide a set of more specific
instructions to handle the next steps.
In this case, we might add
kind of additional information
about the TVs busses.
In this case, we might want to give a link
to closing the account or something
like that.
We'll learn more about different ways
to process inputs in a later video.
In the next video, we'll look at more ways
to evaluate inputs and specifically ways
to ensure that your users
are using the system in a responsible way.