In this video
will focus on checking outputs
generated by the system.
Checking outputs before showing them to
users can be important for ensuring
the quality, relevance and safety
of the responses provided to them.
Or use an automation place or learn
how to use the Moderation API.
But this time the outputs and how to use
additional prompts to the model
to evaluate output quality
before displaying them.
So let's dive into the examples.
We've already discussed the Moderation
API in the context of evaluating inputs.
Now let's revisit it
in the context of checking outputs.
Moderation API can also be used to filter
and moderate outputs generated by
the system itself.
And so here's an example.
So here's
a generated response to the user,
and we're going to use the Moderation
API in the same way
that we saw the earlier video.
So let's see if this output is flagged.
As you can see, this output is not flagged
and has very low scores in all categories
which make sense given the response
in general, it can also be important
to check the outputs.
For example, if you were creating
a chat box for sensitive audiences,
you could use lower thresholds
for flagging outputs.
In general, If the moderation output
indicates that the content is flagged,
you can take appropriate actions
such as responding with a fallback
answer or generating a new response.
Note that as we
improve the models,
they also are becoming less
and less likely
to retain some kind of harmful output.
Another approach for checking outputs
is to ask the model itself,
and the generated was satisfactory,
and if it follows a certain rubric
that you define,
this can be done by providing
the generated output as part of the input
to the model and asking it
to rate the quality of the output.
You can do this in various different ways.
So let's see an example.
So our system method is
you are an assistant that evaluates
whether the customer service
agent responses
sufficiently answer customer questions
and also validates
that all of the assistant
sites
from the product information are correct.
The product information and user
and customer service agent
messages will be limited by three
objectives.
Respond with a y
or end character with no punctuation y.
If the output sufficiently answers
the question
and the response
correctly uses product information and no.
Otherwise I'll put a single letter only.
And you could also use a chain of thought
reasoning prompt for this.
This might be a little bit difficult for
the model to validate both in one stop.
So you could play around with this.
You could also add
some other kind of guidelines.
You could ask give a rubric like a rubric
for an exam or grading an essay.
You could use that kind of format and say,
Does this use a friendly tone in line
with our brand guidelines
and maybe outline
some of your brand guidelines if that's
something that's very important to you.
So let's add our customer message.
So this is the initial message
used to generate this response.
And then also paste
in our product information.
And so this is the product information
we fetched in the previous setup
for all of the products
mentioned in this message
and now will
define a comparison.
So the customer message is
the customer message, product information,
and then the agent response,
which is the response to the customer
that we have from this previous.
So so that's format this
into a messages list
and get the response from the model.
So the model says, yes,
the product information is
correct and the question is answered
sufficiently well.
In general for this kind of evaluation.
I also think it is
better to use a more advanced model
because that is better at reasoning.
So something like JPT for
let's try another example.
So this responses,
life is like a box of chocolates.
So let's add our message to do the output.
Checking.
And the model has determined that this
does not sufficiently answer the question.
We use the Retrieved information.
This question does it use
the Retrieved information correctly?
This is a good
prompt to use if you want to make sure
that the model isn't hallucinating,
which is making up things
that aren't true.
And feel free to pause the video now
and try some of your own customer
messages, responses
and adding product information
to test how this works.
So as you can see,
the model can provide feedback
on the quality of a generated output,
and you can use this feedback to decide
whether to present the output to the user
or to generate any response.
You could even experiment with generating
multiple model responses per user query
and then having the model choose
the best wanted to show the user.
So there's lots of different things
you could try.
In general, checking outputs
using the moderation API is good practice,
but while asking the model
to evaluate its own output might be useful
for immediate feedback
to ensure the quality of responses
in a very small number of cases,
I think it's probably unnecessary
most of the time, especially if you're
using a more advanced model like GBG for
I haven't actually seen many people
do something like this in production.
It would also increase the latency
and cost of your system
because you'd have to wait
for an additional call for the model,
and that's also additional tokens.
If it's really important
for your Apple product that
your error rate is 0.000001%,
then maybe you should try this approach.
But overall, I wouldn't really recommend
that you do this in practice.
In the next video,
we're going to put together
everything we've learned in the evaluate
input section, process
section and checking output section
to build an end to end system.