In this first video, I'd like to share
with you
an overview
of how our launch language models work.
We'll go into how they are trained
as well as details like The Tokenize
and how that can affect the outputs
of when you prompt and them.
And we'll also take a look
at the chat format for our EVs,
which is a way of specifying both system
as well as user
messages and understand
what you can do with that capability.
Let's take a look
first,
How does a large language model work?
You're probably familiar
with the text generation process
where you can give a prompt by voting
and also to fill in
what the things are likely completions.
Given this problem
and they may say because of cream cheese
or my mother's milk or also a friend's,
but how did the model learn to do this
to me,
to use to train and evolve
them is actually supervised learning
in supervised learning.
A computer learns inputs, outputs, or x,
the Y mapping using label training data.
So for example, if you're using supervised
learning to learn
to classify
the sentiment of restaurant reviews,
you might collect a trading set like this
where a review like
the pastrami sandwich is great is labeled
as a positive sentiment review and so on.
And so as though
the food was also negative
and the are great, he was fantastic.
As a positive label.
By the way,
both Eser and I were born in the UK
and so both of us like our gray tea.
And so the process for supervised
learning is typically to get label data
and then train them all to own data.
And after training you can
then deploy and called the model
and give it a new restaurant
review like this piece of have had
you hopefully I'll put it
that has a positive sentiment.
It turns out that supervised learning
is a code building block for training.
Large language models.
Specifically a large language
model can be built by using supervised
learning to repeatedly predict
the next word.
Let's say that in your training
sets of a lot of text data,
you have two centers.
My favorite food is a
bagel with cream cheese. And
then this
sentence is turned into a sequence
of training examples
where, given the sentence fragments,
my favorite fruit is a
If you want to predict the next one in
this case was bagel
or given the sentence fragment
or sentence prefix.
My favorite food is a bagel.
The next word in this case would be with
and so on.
And given a large training
set of hundreds of billions or sometimes
even more, whereas you can
then create a massive training set
where you can start off with part
of a sentence or part of a piece of text,
and repeatedly asked the language model to
learn to predict what is the next words.
So today there are broadly two
major types of large language models.
The first is a base
and the second,
which is what is increasingly
used, is the instruction to know.
So the base all repeatedly predicts
the next word based on
texts, training, data.
And so if I give it a prompt,
once upon a time there was a unicorn,
then it me by repeatedly predicting
one word at a time, come up with a feature
and it tells a story about the unicorn
living in a magical forest
with all unicorn friends.
Now the downside of this
is that if you were to prompt it with
what is a couple of friends,
quite plausible that on the internet
there might be a list of quiz questions
about friends.
So me complete this
with what this friends is like to say
that you want this
friends, population and so on.
But what
you really want is you want it to tell you
what is the couple of friends probably,
rather than list all these questions.
So the instructions you learn
instead tries to follow instructions
and will hopefully say
the couple of friends is Paris.
How do you go from a base
to an instruction tuned? Oh,
this is what the process of training
and instruction to like chatting busy.
Looks like your first trailer
based on the lot of data.
So hundreds of billions of words.
Maybe even more.
And this is a process
that can take months on
a large supercomputing system.
After you've trained the base alone,
you would then further train the model
by fine
tuning it on a smaller set of examples
where the output follows
an input instruction.
And so, for example,
you may have contractors help.
You write a lot of examples
of an instruction and then a good response
to an instruction,
and that creates a training set
to carry out this additional fine tuning.
So the lesson for the well, this the next
what if is trying to
follow an instruction
after that
to improve the quality of the output.
A common process now is to obtain human
ratings of the quality
of many different outputs on criteria,
such as whether the output is helpful,
honest and harmless,
and you can then further tune the element
to increase the probability of a
generating the more highly rated upwards.
And the most common technique to do
this is RH, which stands
for reinforcement
Learning from Human feedback.
And. WHEREAS, training the base hour
can take months, the process
of going from the base
to the instruction to, you know,
can be done in maybe days on much more
on a much more modest sized dataset,
a much more modest sized
computational resources.
So this is how you would use
an 11 on content for the few libraries.
So I'm going to load my open a key here.
I'll say a little bit more
about this later in this video.
And here's a helper function
to get a completion given a prompt
if you have not yet installed the open
the AI package on your computer,
you might have to run PIP, install
open the I,
but I already have an install here
so I we'll run that
and then shift into to run this.
And now I can set response equals
get completion.
What is the capital of France
and hopefully
it will
give me a good result.
Now about now in the description
that the launch language model so far
I talked about it
as predicting one at a time.
But there's actually one more important
technical detail.
If you were to tell it,
take the letters into work where lollipop
and reverse them.
This seems like an easy task.
Maybe like a four year
euro could do this task.
But if you were to ask Chiquita
to do this,
it actually outputs a somewhat garbled
whatever this is, this is not lollipop.
This is not lollipop us reverse.
So why is Gypsy unable to do what
seems like a relatively simple task?
It turns out that this one more
important detail for how large language
model works, which is it doesn't actually
repeatedly predict the next words.
It is that it repeatedly predicts
the next token.
And what that actually does is
it would take a sequence of characters
like learning new things is fun and group
the characters together to form tokens
that comprise comedy
occurring sequences of characters.
So here learning new things is fun.
Each of them is a fairly common word,
and so each token corresponds
to one word or one word in a space
or an exclamation mark.
But if you were to give it input
with some somewhat less frequently used
words like prompting as powerful
developer to the word
prompting is still not that common
in the English language,
but certainly gaining in popularity.
And so prompting is actually broken down
to three tokens with prompt
and in because there's three a commonly
occurring sequences of letters.
And if you were to give it the word
lollipop, the token
those are actually breaks down into three
tokens L and all and E pop.
And because it isn't seeing
the individual letters is instead
CVC tokens is more difficult for it
to correctly
print out these letters in reverse order.
So here's a trick you can use to fix this.
If I were to add dashes
between these letters
and spaces would work
to other things would were too.
And tell it to put those in lollipop
and reverse them.
Then it actually does a much better
job. This.
Oh, I pop out.
And the reason for that is
if you pass a lollipop
with dashes in between the letters,
it tokenize
each of these characters into individual
token, making it easier for it
to see the individual letters
and print them out in reverse order.
So if you ever wants to use GBC
to play a word game,
like where they'll scrabble something,
this nifty trick hopes
it better see
the individual letters of the words
for the English language.
One token, roughly on average corresponds
to about four characters
or about three quarters of a words.
And so different large language
models will often have different limits
on the number of input plus output tokens
it can accept.
The input is often called the contacts
and the output is often
called the completion
and the model Gypsy 3.5 Terrible.
For example, the most commonly used H.A.
model has a limit of roughly 4000 tokens
and the inputs plus output.
So if you try to feed in an input context
as much longer than did,
so actually throw
in the exception on generated error.
Next, I want to share with you
another powerful way to use an API
which involves specifying separate system
user and assistance messages.
Let me show you an example
then we can explain in more detail
what is actually doing.
Here's a new helper function
called Get completion from Messages.
And when we prompt as our end,
we are going to give it multiple messages.
Just an example of what you can do.
I'm going to specify
first a message and the row of a system.
So there's a system message
and the contents of the system messages
you're in,
the system responds to the sound of Dr.
Seuss.
Then I'm going to specify a user message.
So the role of the second message is road
user.
And the content of this is write me
a very short poem about a happy carrot.
And so let's run that.
And with temperature equals one,
I actually never know
what's going to come out,
but okay, that's a cool poem.
Oh, how much of this carrot that I see
and it actually runs pretty well.
All right, well done.
And so in this
example, the system message specifies
the overall tone
of what you want
the large language model to do.
And the user message is a specific
instruction that you wanted to carry out.
Given this higher level behavior.
There was specified in the system message.
Here's
an illustration of how it all works.
So this is how the chat format works.
The system message sets the overall tone,
the behavior of the launch language model
or the assistant.
And then when you give their user message,
such as maybe such as a
tell me a joke or write me a poem,
it will then output
an appropriate response following
what you asked for and did use the message
and consistent with the overall behavior
set in the system message.
And by the way,
although I'm not illustrating it here,
if you want to use this
in a multi tone conversation,
you can also input assistant messages
in this messages format
to let Chickpea know what it had
previously said.
If you wanted to continue the conversation
based on things
that have previously said as well.
But here are a few more examples
if you want to set the tone
to tell it to have a one sentence
long output, then in the system message,
I can say all your responses
must be one sentence long.
And when I execute this it outputs.
A single sentence is no longer a plea.
Another the solved
after this is a single sentence.
There's a story about the happy carrots.
And if we want to combine
both specifying the style and the length,
then I can use the system message to say
you're an assistant.
In response to start of the series,
all your sentences must
be one sentence long, and now
this generates a nice one sentence point.
It was always smiling and never scary.
I like that. This a very happy point in.
And then lastly, just for fun,
if you are using an L
and you want to know how many tokens are
you using, here's a hope.
The function
that is a little bit more sophisticated
in that it gets a response from the open
AI API endpoint
and then it uses other values
in the response to tell you how many
prompt tokens, completion tokens and total
tokens were used in your API call.
Let me define that.
And if I run this now, here's
the response.
And here is
a count of how many tokens we use.
So this output, which had 55 tokens,
whereas the prompt inputs had 37 tokens,
So this used up 92 tokens
altogether
without using our models in practice.
I don't worry that much frankly,
about the number of tokens I'm using.
Maybe one case where it might be worth
checking the number of tokens is
if you're worried
that the user may giving you too long
and inputs that exceeds the 4000 or so
token limits of empathy,
in which case you could double check
how many tokens it was
and truncated to make sure you stay within
the input token
limit of the launch language model.
Now I want to share with you one more tip
for how to use a large language model
called the Open API requires
using an API key this tied to either
a free or a paid account.
And so many developers will write the API
key in plaintext
like this into their Jupyter notebook.
And this is a less secure way
of using API keys
that I would not recommend
you use because it's just too easy
to share this notebook with someone else
or check this into a GitHub or something
and does end up leaking your API key
to someone else.
In contrast,
what you saw me do and the Jupyter
notebook
was this piece of code where I use
a library dot env and then run.
This commands a little to find out
is to read a local file
which is called end
that contains my secret key.
And so with this code snippet
I have locally stored a file contents
that contains my API key and this loads it
into the operating systems
environmental variable.
And then our start get ends
open the API key stores
into this variable.
And in this whole process,
I don't ever have to enter the API
key in plaintext in unencrypted plaintext
into my true for the notebook.
So this is a relatively more secure
and a better way to access the API.
And in fact this is a general method
for storing different API keys
from lots of different online services
that you might want to use.
They call for every Jupyter notebook.
Lastly, I think
the degree to which
prompting this revolutionizing
application
development is still underappreciated
in the traditional supervised machine
learning workflow like the restaurant
Review central classification example
that I touched on just now.
If you want to build a classifier
to classify restaurant review
positive or negative sentiments, you
at first get a bunch of label data, maybe
hundreds of examples this might take,
I don't know, weeks, maybe a month.
Then you would train a model on data
and getting an appropriate
open source model,
tuning on the model, evaluating it.
That might take days, weeks,
maybe even a few months.
And then you might have
to find a call service to deploy it
and then a model upload to the cloud
and then run the model
and finally be able to call your model.
And that's, again, not uncommon
for this to take a team
a few months to get working.
In contrast
with prompting base machine learning,
When you have a text application,
you can specify a problem.
This can take minutes, maybe hours,
if you need to iterate a few times
to get an effective prompt
and then in hours,
maybe at most days,
but frankly more often hours
you can have this running using API calls
and start making calls to the model.
And once you've done that in
just maybe minutes or hours, you can start
calling the model
and start making inferences.
And so there are applications
that used to take me maybe
six months or a year to build
that you can now build in minutes
or hours, maybe very small numbers of days
using prompting,
and this is revolutionizing
what applications can be built quickly.
One important caveat this applies
to many unstructured data applications,
including specifically text applications
and maybe
increasingly vision applications.
Although the vision technology
is much less mature
now, this kind of getting there,
this recipe doesn't really work
for structured either applications,
meaning machine learning applications on
days with lots of numerical values
in Excel spreadsheet,
say the for applications
to which this does apply.
The fact that a component can be built
so quickly
is changing the workflow
of how the entire system might be built.
Though the entire system
may still take days or weeks or something,
but at least this piece of
it can be done much faster.
And so with that, let's go on
to the next video where user will show
how to use these components to evaluate
input to a customer service assistant.
And this will be part of a bigger example
that you see developed
through this course
for building a customer service
assistant for an online retailer.